Venkataramana Hari 4212 Jefferson Oaks Circle Apartment C Fairfax, VA - 22033 Contact # 571-249-8342

Email: venkatatamanahari@yahoo.com

Summary

20 years of development of application experience using CICS, TSO, ISPF, VSAM, COBOL, DB2, IMS, JCL, ENDEAVOR, MQ series with SDLC methodology. My industry experience includes Insurance Claims, Accident Claims, Asset Management Financial Applications, Retail and Management Account Projects and Government Consulting with Agile project Management methodology.

Training completed

Project Manage Management

Industry Experience

Water Fall

Agile Methodology

ITIL

- Navy Federal Credit Union: Under this line of business, we have multiple projects, Member Services, Mobile Banking, Mortgage, Auto Loans, Accounts, certificates and bank related application.
- Capital One Financial Systems: Under this line of business, we have three projects running and they are CRS Transactions to ODS, Data Quality for Cards and bank application.
- Health Insurance claims process for WellPoint and Carefirst: This system consists of Claims Validation, Eligibility and calculation of Claim Payment and generation of explanation of benefits (EOB)
- Data Validation and Testing (SSA): This system consists PII data and the data needed to be sanitized as per business rules, System uses Dsicrit component to define rules and

this component will be used with Data solutions to produce sanitized data output using input file.

- Diagnosis code conversion from ICD 9 to ICD10: This system consists of online and batch process. Claims are entered and adjudicated thru on line system. Batch system updates the DB2 tables and FOCUS programs are used to generate reports and mail to users.
- Accident Claims for Corporate Systems: New system is designed for three-tier architecture. The claim data is enterer thru front end on line and the information is passed to MQ series and mainframe reads MQ and processes the claim and sends payment and EOB to front end.
- Merchandise Purchasing System (MPS) for BJ's: This system consists of
 online and batch process. Products are bought from vendor system. Delivery of
 products of purchase order is verified by distribution and center and that triggers
 payments to Vendor. From distribution center products are transported to point of
 sales.
- Early Retiree Reinsurance Program (ERRP) for Health and Human Services:
 This project is developed to reduce the out of pocket expenses for employees on their health clams. The funds are granted to employers and it is used to cover health claims for early retiree employees. Employees who are 55 and more are eligible for ERRP
- Home Loan Modification for FreddieMac: The existing loan system has balance on the loan amount. This loan amount is split in two portions, one is interest bearing balance and another is non interest balance The loans with new data are stored in "Cash Manager System" and are updated by monthly payment file feed from mainframe.
- New Billing Engine System for Verizon: The batch system to generate bills and to be tested before they are sent to customers and new online system allowed view bills online and bills sent to customer in regular PDF format.

Roles/Responsibilities

- Development and enhancement of online and batch COBOL programs for client applications
- Enhancement of COBOL, CICS programs to convert to MQ series compatible
- Used **XPEDITOR** tool to debug and fix problems in **COBOL** Programs.

- Setting up GDG for projects
- Used SPUFI and QMF in DB2 for reports.
- Development and Enhancement of JCL and PROCS for batch processing
- Development of Test Plans and Test Cases for System and User Acceptance
 Test using Mercury Quality Center
- Impact Analysis of System Changes based on Change Requests from Users
- Attend Business User Group meetings to capture requirements
- Development of Technical Specification Documents from Requirement documents
- Development of Process flow diagrams using Vision
- Coordination of work with Vendors for SLA
- Knowledge Transfer Session meetings
- Weekly status reports to Management.

Skills Utilized:

COBOL, DB2, CICS, IMS DB/DC, JCL, PROCS, VSAM, ENDEVOR, EXPEDITOR, EZTTRIEVE, TSO, ISPF, GDG MQ Series, Mercury Quality Center, SYNCSORT, IDCAMS, IEBGENER, Mainframe Tools and Utilities, Java, ORACLE, MS Project, Microsoft Word, Excel, Power Point, MS Access, DBASE III Plus and Outlook.

EDUCATION:

Colleges Attended:

 College of Engineering, Osmania University Hyderabad India, June 1981 to June 1985

Work History

Navy Federal Credit Union Senior Mainframe Developer 12/2013 to 11/13/2015

WiPRO information Technology

Senior Mainframe Developer 07/2013 to 12/2003 Client: Capital One

Collabera Mainframe Developer 10/2012 to 11/2012 Client: IBM Global

Bowhead Systems Management, Inc. Mainframe Developer 06/2012 to 09/30/2012 Client: SSA

Netvision Resources
Mainframe Developer
11/2011 to 03//2012
Client: Department of Mental Health

UST Global On site Mainframe Developer 01//2011 to 04/2011 Client: BJ

Saxon Info tech Senior Mainframe Developer 06//2010 to 12/2010 Client: Health Human Services

Syneren Technology Senior Mainframe Developer 02//2010 to 04/2010 Client: Department of Transportation

Spectrum Careers Senior Mainframe Developer 06//2009 to 09/2009 Client: Freddie Mac

BSG Senior Mainframe Developer 07//2008 to 12/2008 Client: Amtrak

Collabera Mainframe Developer 04//2007 to 06/2008 Client: Verizon
Apex Systems
Mainframe Developer
03//2006 to 09/2006

Client: SSA

Bay Tek Consulting
Mainframe Developer
11/2005 to 02/2006
Client: Department of Public Corrections

GEICO Senior Mainframe Developer 04/2005 to 10/2005

CareFirst Lead Mainframe Programmer Analyst 04/2001 to 02/2003

Emplify Consulting 10/1994 to 03/2001 Mainframe Developer